Guide to the Albert Waldo Snoke Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- WRITINGS, 1937-1988; Series II
  - Bibliographic items
    - 23. Horse and Buggy Days, 1954 (Box 34, Folder 77)
    - 24. Hospital Administration is a Profession--Not a Business, 1954-1955 (Box 34, Folder 78)
    - 25. Design for Future Health Needs, 1955 (Box 34, Folder 79)
    - 26. A Challenge to Physicians and Hospitals, 1955 (Box 34, Folder 80)
    - 27. Nursing Service and Education, 1956 (Box 34, Folder 81)
    - 28. Hospital Practice of Medicine--A Cliche for Today, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 82)
    - 30. Hospitals--Their Current and Future Problems, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 83)
    - 31. The Future Role of Hospitals in Medical Care, 1958 (Box 34, Folder 84)
    - 32. Recommendations of the American Hospital Association, 1958 (Box 34, Folder 85)
    - 33. The Responsibility of Hospitals for Nursing Service, 1958 (Box 34, Folder 86)
    - 34. Financial Relationships Between Radiologists and Hospitals, 1958 (Box 34, Folder 87)
    - 35. The Teaching Hospital--Its Responsibilities and Conflicts, 1960 (Box 34, Folder 88)
    - 35a. Internship Debate, 1961 (Box 34, Folder 89)
    - 36. Meeting Your Responsibility for High Quality Care, 1961 (Box 34, Folder 90)
    - 36a. Planning for Connecticut Regional Planning Through Partnership of Voluntary and Governmental Agencies, 1961 (Box 34, Folder 91)
    - 36b. Organization for Health Care for the Sixties, 1961 (Box 34, Folder 92)
    - 37. The Teaching Hospital, 1961-1962 (Box 34, Folder 93)
    - 37a. Restricting Diagnostic Radiology to In-Patients Doesn't Make Sense, 1962 (Box 34, Folder 94)
    - 38. How Kerr-Mills Works in Connecticut, 1963 (Box 34, Folder 95)
    - 38a. The Role of the Hospital in Research--Bystander or Participant?, 1963-1964 (Box 34, Folder 96)
    - 39. Health Care of the Aged, 1963 (Box 34, Folder 97)
    - 40. Financial Relationships Between Radiologists and Hospitals, 1964 (Box 34, Folder 98)
    - 41. Hospitals and Human Rights, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 99)
    - 41a. Distinguished Service Award Interview with A. W. Snoke, M. D., 1965-1966 (Box 34, Folder 100)
    - 41b. American Hospital Association Distinguished Service Award Speech, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 101)
    - 42. The Changing Philosophy of Hospital Economics, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 102)
    - 43. Challenge to Health Care Leaders: Stop Fighting and Start Leading, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 103)
    - 45. Medicare Year One: A Critical Appraisal, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 104)
    - 46. Local, Regional, and National Hospital Planning: The Role of the Teaching Hospital, 1967-1968 (Box 34, Folder 105)
    - 47. The Unsolved Problem of the Career Professional in the Establishment of National Health Policy, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 106)
    - 48. The Practicing Physician's Role in Hospital Management--A Consultant's View, 1969-1972 (Box 35, Folder 107)
    - 49. Teaching and Research Facilities, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 108)
    - 50. Involving Physicians in Hospital Management, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 109)
    - 51. The Response of Public Health to a Changing World, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 110)
    - 52. Regional Planning: Pious Platitude or Practical Implementation, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 111)
    - 53a. Comprehensive Health Planning, State of Illinois, 1970-1972 (Box 35, Folder 112)
    - 53b. Report of the Inter-Agency Task Force on Long-Term Care Facilities, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 113)
    - 53c. Cooperative Study of Health Manpower Licensure Rules, Regulations, and Procedures, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 114)
    - 53d. The Illinois Program for Services to the Aging, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 115)
    - 53f. Health Services Coordination Program of Northeastern Illinois, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 116)
    - 53h. Comprehensive Health Planning and Administrative Objectives, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 117)
    - 53i. Illinois Health Program, 1969-1973 (Box 35, Folder 118)
    - 54. The Responsibility of the Health Establishment for the Health Care of People, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 119)
    - 55. Health and Social Services in the State of Illinois, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 120-121)
      See also: Series I, folder 293
    - 56. The Role and Responsibility of a State in Promoting Good Health for its People, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 122)
    - 57. The Containment of Health Costs and Improvement of the Management, Quality and Delivery of Health and Social Services in Connecticut. A Proposal to Governor Meskill, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 123)
    - 58. Hospitals and State Government: A Conversation with Albert W. Snoke, M. D., 1973 (Box 35, Folder 124)
    - 59. The Future of the Connecticut Regional Medical Program, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 125)
    - 60. Health Care Delivery--A Blueprint for Change, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 126)
    - 60a. 50th Anniversary--International Scout Jamboree at Copenhagen, Denmark, 1975 (Box 36, Folder 127)
    - 61a,b. The Role of the State in the Health and Welfare of its People: Forward and Introduction, 1975 (Box 36, Folder 128)
    - 61c. The Role of the State in the Health and Welfare of its People: Regionalization--Options for Health Service Areas in Connecticut, 1975 (Box 36, Folder 129)
    - 61d. The Role of the State in the Health and Welfare of its People: Planning for Health Affairs and the Impact Thereon of P. L. 93-641, 1975 (Box 36, Folder 130)
    - 61e. The State Role in the Regulation of the Health Delivery System
      See: folder 132
    - 61f. The Role of the State in the Health and Welfare of its People: The Organization and Administration of a State for Health and Social Affairs, 1975 (Box 36, Folder 131)
    - 61g. Recommendation for the State of Connecticut submitted to the Executive Director of the New Haven Health Care, Inc., 1975 Jun
      See: Series I, folder 117
    - 62. The State Role in the Regulation of the Health Delivery System, 1975 (Box 36, Folder 132)
    - 63. Linking Private, Public Energies in Health and Welfare Planning, 1976 (Box 36, Folder 133)
    - 64. The Connecticut Regional Medical Program--An Editorial, 1976 (Box 36, Folder 134)
    - 65. Regionalization in the State of Connecticut, 1976 (Box 36, Folder 135)
    - 66. A Guide to Health Facilities, Personnel and Management. The Future, 1976-1977 (Box 37, Folder 136)
    - 67. The Improvement of Health and Social Services (Human Services) in the State of Connecticut, 1977 (Box 37, Folder 137)
    - 68. Improving the Delivery of Health and Social Services (Human Services) by the State of Connecticut, 1977 (Box 37, Folder 138)
    - 69. Memorandum on "Public Guaranteed Health Protection", 1978 (Box 37, Folder 139)
    - 70. Let's Challenge the Government for a Change!, 1978 (Box 37, Folder 140)
    - 71. The Stanford University Teaching Hospital, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 141)
    - 72. National Health Insurance: How Can It Be Successfully Implemented?, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 142)
    - 73. What Good is Legislation--or Planning--if we Can't Make it Work?, 1981-1982 (Box 37, Folder 143)
  - Non-bibliographic items
    - 1939 (Box 37, Folder 144)
    - 1948 (Box 37, Folder 145)
    - 1951 (Box 37, Folder 146)
    - 1952 (Box 37, Folder 147)
    - 1953 (Box 37, Folder 148)
    - 1954 (Box 37, Folder 149)
    - 1955 (Box 37, Folder 150)
    - 1955, Current Legal Status of Hospital-Physician Relations (Box 37, Folder 151)
    - 1956 (Box 37, Folder 152)
    - 1957 (Box 37, Folder 153)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 37, Folder 154)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 37, Folder 155)
    - 1961, Principles of Hospital-Radiologist Relationships (Box 37, Folder 156)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 37, Folder 157)
    - 1964 (Box 37, Folder 158)
    - 1965 (Box 38, Folder 159)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 38, Folder 160-161)
    - 1969 (Box 38, Folder 162)
    - 1970 (Box 38, Folder 163)
    - 1972 (Box 38, Folder 164)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 38, Folder 165)
    - 1975 (Box 38, Folder 166)
    - 1975, A Voluntary State Organization for the Health and Welfare of People (Box 38, Folder 167)
    - 1977 (Box 38, Folder 168)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 38, Folder 169)
    - 1978-1981, Proposed book on the implementation of a national health care program (Box 38, Folder 170-172)
      See also: Series I, folders 70, 82, 98, 102, 128, 147, 152, 255, 280, 385, 387
    - 1980 (Box 39, Folder 173-174)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 39, Folder 175)
    - 1984 (Box 39, Folder 176)
    - 1987 (Box 39, Folder 177)
    - 1987, Hospitals, Health, and People
      - Final copy (Box 39, Folder 178)
        See also: Series I, folders 17, 121, 166-167, 257-258, 387, 430
      - Drafts for dedication (Box 39, Folder 179)
      - Drafts [may also have been used for the Oral history] (Box 39, Folder 180)
      - Drafts (Box 39, Folder 181)
      - Comments by James Hague on chapter draft of Hospitals, health, and People, 1 (Box 58)
      - Notes [may also have been used for proposed book no. 2] (Box 39, Folder 182)
      - Publicity, reviews (Box 39, Folder 183)
    - 1987, Telephone Talk [WELI radio interview and call-in program concerning Hospitals, Health, and People ], 1 (Box 59)
    - 1987, oral history (Box 40, Folder 184-185)
    - 1988, proposed "book no. 2" (Box 40, Folder 186-187)
    - n.d., containment of health costs: rate review commissions (Box 40, Folder 188)
- TOPICAL FILES, 1937-1982; Series III
  This series is composed of files dealing with particular subjects of interest to Snoke during his long career in health care administration. For any particular topic the files may include background material in the form of brochures, pamphlets, reports, and the like (though readily available published materials have been removed from the collection), correspondence, notes, and memoranda.
  The series begins with files on health planning which relate to Snoke's general interest in federal legislation dealing with comprehensive state health planning agencies and national health insurance. The series continues with files specifically concerning health planning in Connecticut, which relate to attempts during the late 1960s and 1970s to reorganize the structure of state government. Of particular concern was the regionalization of state medical programs and the adequate protection of human resources. Snoke at this time served on the Select Advisory Panel of the Connecticut Association for Human Services, and material in these files documents the work of the panel.
  Material filed under the heading "Hospital Administration" concerns the proper relationship between hospitals and physicians. Professional associations for medical specialists contended that doctors could not be salaried staff of a hospital. Thus for a hospital to have physicians as paid staff amounted to the unethical corporate practice of medicine. Through the 1950s and early 1960s, Snoke was involved in attempts by the American Hospital Association to achieve harmonious relationships with medical specialists and to attempt to define common ground for negotiating financial relationships between hospitals and anesthesiologists, pathologists, and radiologists. The files include position papers and background material, including materials from Snoke's participation in the "Iowa Case," where the issue of corporate practice of medicine was actually brought to trial.
  The remaining files in the series date from Snoke's service as coordinator of health services in Illinois. They include information on health planning agencies in different regions around the state as well as on particular issues such as cost containment. Files on a conference on the role of the state in health planning, convened by the governor of Illinois, include a copy of the notebook given to each conference participant and the transcript of the proceedings.
  - Health planning [background material]
    - Comprehensive Health Planning (PL89-749), 1966-1967 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Comprehensive Health Planning Agencies, 1972-1973 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - National Health Insurance, 1975-1983 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - National Health Planning and Resources Development Act (PL93-641), 1974-1979 (Box 41, Folder 4-5)
  - Connecticut health planning [special concern with state reorganization in the 1970s-early 1980s]
    - General
      - 1971-1982 (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - 1976 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Connecticut (state)
      - Committee on the Structure of State Government (Filer Committee), 1976-1977 (Box 41, Folder 8)
      - Council on Human Services, 1975-1977 (Box 41, Folder 9)
      - Human Resources Reorganization Commission, 1977-1979 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Connecticut Association for Human Services. Select Advisory Panel
      - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 42, Folder 11-12)
      - Report, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Connecticut Regional Medical Program
      See also: Series I, folders 74, 270, 271-273
      - 1967-1968 (Box 42, Folder 14)
      - 1973 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Connecticut regionalization, 1975-1976 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - Notes, 1937-1982 (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Hospital Administration [special concern with hospital-physician relationships]
    - Hospital-physician relationships, 1947-1983, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 18-21)
      See also: Series I, folders 10-15, 20, 60 (Clark), 374
    - Anesthesiology, 1951-1961 (Box 43, Folder 22)
    - Corporate practice of medicine, 1955-1963 (Box 43, Folder 23)
    - Corporate practice of medicine: rulings by states' attorneys general, 1950-1962 (Box 43, Folder 24)
    - Iowa case, 1954-1957 (Box 43, Folder 25-27)
      See also: Series I, folders 10-15, 20, 100, 190, 165, 166-167, 215, 386
    - Medicare, 1965-1966 (Box 44, Folder 28)
    - Nursing, 1956-1957 (Box 44, Folder 29)
    - Pathology, 1938-1984 (Box 44, Folder 30)
      See also: Series I, folder 23
    - Principles of reimbursement, 1951-1953 (Box 44, Folder 31)
    - Radiology, 1945-1972 (Box 44, Folder 32-33)
      See also: Series I, folders 9, 10-15, 84, 108, 150, 170, 210, 386
  - Illinois Coordinator of Health Services
    See also: Series I, folders 35, 39, 114, 122, 134, 138, 180, 187, 223-225, 253, 431, 435
    - Comprehensive health planning [background material]
      - General, 1968-1972 (Box 45, Folder 34-35)
      - Institute of Government and Public Affairs (Box 45, Folder 36-39)
      - Mood, Eric
        - Comprehensive Health Planning and the Environment in Illinois, 1972 (Box 45, Folder 40)
        - Environmental Health in Illinois, 1972 (Box 45, Folder 41)
      - Memoranda, 1971-1972 (Box 45, Folder 42)
    - Comprehensive State Health Planning Agency
      - Background material, 1966-1971 (Box 45, Folder 43)
      - Reports, 1972 (Box 45, Folder 44)
    - Comprehensive State Health Planning Agency, Advisory Council
      - General, 1972 (Box 46, Folder 45)
      - Reference manual, 1972 (Box 46, Folder 46-48)
    - Cook County, 1971-1972 (Box 46, Folder 49)
    - Costs and cost containment
      - Background material, 1971-1972 (Box 46, Folder 50)
      - Memoranda, 1971-1972 (Box 46, Folder 51)
    - Northeastern Illinois, 1971 (Box 46, Folder 52)
    - People Services Task Force, 1972-1973 (Box 46, Folder 53)
    - The Role and Responsibility of a State in Promoting Good Health for Its People (Governor's Invitational Conference)
      - Participants' notebook, 1972 Feb (Box 46, Folder 54)
      - Edited transcript and Ogilvie's remarks, 1972 Feb (Box 47, Folder 55-59)
      - Photographs
        See: Series V, folder 27
- Personal and Family Papers, 1861-1988; Series IV
  This series is composed of papers and memorabilia of several Hamilton, Snoke and Storey family members. The papers have been grouped by family or individual and then arranged alphabetically by type of material. The series includes several types of personal papers of Albert Snoke, such as biographical sketches, articles about him, and travel diaries. There is also a significant quantity of material relating to Parnie Storey Snoke, including her correspondence, research notes, files from her civic activities, and school memorabilia. Filed under various members of the Storey family are several types of material which relate to Palo Alto, California and Stanford University. The oldest material in the series is that for Riley Storey and includes diaries kept by him during his military service in the Civil War.
  - Hamilton family, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Snoke, Albert
    - Address book, 1964 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Articles about, ca., 1946-1972 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Awards, ca., 1933-1986 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      See also: Oversize, folders 2-3
    - Bibliography, 1937-1987 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Biographical sketch, ca., 1946-1984 (Box 48, Folder 6)
      See also: Series II, folder 184
    - Certificates
      See: Oversize, folders 2-3
    - Christmas cards, Snoke family, 1939-1972 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Clippings about, ca., 1944-1986 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Illinois [clippings, publicity], 1969-1974 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Log of telephone messages, 1983 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Memorabilia, 1951-1978 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - School, 1920-1979 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Travel diaries and letters, 1973, 1977-1978 (Box 48, Folder 13-15)
  - Snoke, Frank McElwain: "Some Snoke Families,", 1979 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Snoke, Parnie Storey
    - General files
      - A-L, ca., 1924-1972 (Box 49, Folder 17)
      - M-Z, ca., 1929-1966 (Box 49, Folder 18)
      - American Hospital Association, ca., 1952-1958 (Box 49, Folder 19)
      - Delta Gamma, ca., 1942-1958 (Box 49, Folder 20)
      - Grace-New Haven Community Hospital, ca., 1952-1958 (Box 49, Folder 21)
      - Masur, Jack, ca., 1959-1967 (Box 49, Folder 22)
      - Snoke family, 1943 (Box 49, Folder 23)
      - Stanford University, 1932-1962 (Box 49, Folder 24)
      - Storey family, 1922-1945 (Box 49, Folder 25)
      - Yale University, ca., 1959-1961 (Box 49, Folder 26)
      - Unidentified, ca., 1959-1961 (Box 49, Folder 27)
    - Awards, certificates, and diplomas, ca., 1921-1966 (Box 49, Folder 28)
    - Biographical material, ca., 1959-1981 (Box 49, Folder 29)
    - Birthday book, ca., 1972 (Box 49, Folder 30)
    - Clippings, ca., 1961-1981 (Box 49, Folder 31)
    - Legal papers, 1940 (Box 49, Folder 32)
    - Memorabilia, ca., 1966-1967 (Box 49, Folder 33)
    - Programs: American Hospital Association, 1964-1979 (Box 49, Folder 34)
    - Research and writings, 1958-1967 (Box 50, Folder 35-36)
    - School memorabilia
      - General, 1920-1928 (Box 50, Folder 37)
      - Dance cards, 1925-1934 (Box 50, Folder 38)
      - Programs, 1928-1932 (Box 50, Folder 39)
  - Snoke family, ca., 1905-1907 (Box 50, Folder 40)
  - Storey, Margaret Hamilton, 1920-1943 (Box 50, Folder 41)
  - Storey, Marion, ca., 1934 (Box 50, Folder 42)
  - Storey, Parnie Hamilton, 1891-1935 (Box 50, Folder 43)
  - Storey, Parnie Hamilton and Thomas A., 1894-1905 (Box 50, Folder 44)
  - Storey, Riley C.
    - General, 1863-1901 (Box 50, Folder 45)
    - Autograph book; notebook of family history, ca., 1866-1900 (Box 50, Folder 46)
    - Diaries, 1861-1867 (Box 51, Folder 47)
  - Storey, Rosa Shafer, 1902-1930 (Box 51, Folder 48)
  - Storey, Thomas Andrew, 1892-1943 (Box 51, Folder 49)
  - Unidentified family, ca., 1929-1936 (Box 51, Folder 50)
- Photographs, 1907-1988; Series V
  This series is composed of photographs of Albert Snoke, various members of the Snoke and Storey families, friends, and professional acquaintances. Photographs of Snoke and of family members are arranged at the beginning of the series under the heading "Family." These photographs include baby pictures and formal portraits. The "Family" photographs are followed by photographs arranged in chronological order, which show Snoke at various times or at particular events. This grouping includes photographs from Snoke's camping trips on Mount Rainier and other scouting events as well as those from speaking engagements and award ceremonies. Photographs filed under the heading "Groups" include photographs of assemblages of association members, conference participants, and students. Portraits, many of them autographed by Snoke's friends and colleagues, are filed alphabetically under the heading "Individuals" at the end of the series.
  Photographs that came to Snoke as enclosures in letters from friends have, generally, been left with their letter of transmittal. Only photographs that portray Snoke have been moved to this series. Additional photographs may be found in Series I, folders 56, 116, 125, 129, 140, 153, 163, 190, 200, 239, 249, 267, 295, 300, 319, 340, 342, 343, 352, 355, 357, 400, 403, 414, 432, and 436. There are also photographs in Series IV, folders 17 and 27.
  - Family
    - Snoke, Albert
      - General, 1907-1950 (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Portraits, ca., 1941-1978 (Box 52, Folder 2-4)
      - With Parnie, ca., 1956-1979 (Box 52, Folder 5)
        See also: folder 9
    - Snoke, Barbara, 1909 (Box 52, Folder 6)
      See also: folder 14
    - Snoke, Parnie
      - Album, 1925-1932 (Box 52, Folder 7)
      - General, 1909-1980 (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - With Albert and family, ca., 1944-1958 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Snoke, Thomas, Arthur, and Michael
      - Childhood, 1944-1960 (Box 53, Folder 10)
      - Adults [includes wives and children], ca., 1977-1983 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Storey family, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified, 1920, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Chronological
    - 1917-1920s [childhood and scouting album] (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - 1920s-1930s [high school and scouting events; college] (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - 1931 [Mount Rainier] (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - 1932-1935 [first year of marriage, including trips to Point Sebastien, Oregon, and Mount Rainier] (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - 1946-1949 (Box 53, Folder 18)
    - 1953-1959 (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - 1954 [Connecticut Hospital Association annual meeting] (Box 53, Folder 20)
    - 1956 [Texas Hospital Association] (Box 53, Folder 21)
    - 1961-1969 (Box 53, Folder 22)
    - 1962 [Providence Hospital] (Box 53, Folder 23)
    - 1965 [American Hospital Association Distinguished Service Award] (Box 53, Folder 24)
    - 1968 [spring reception] (Box 53, Folder 25)
    - 1971 [Illinois governor's Christmas party] (Box 53, Folder 26)
    - 1972
      - The Role and Responsibility of the State in Promoting Good Health for Its People (Governor's Invitational Conference) (Box 53, Folder 27)
      - Chicago College of Osteopathy honorary doctorate (Box 53, Folder 28)
      - Connecticut Hospital Association Distinguished Service Award (Box 53, Folder 29)
    - 1973-1986 (Box 53, Folder 30)
    - n.d. (Box 53, Folder 31)
      See also: Oversize, folder 4
  - Groups
    - American Association of Hospital Consultants, 1965 (Box 53, Folder 32)
    - American Hospital Association, 1956-1986 (Box 53, Folder 33)
    - Brookings Institution (Sea Island), 1967 (Box 53, Folder 34)
    - CTH, 1952,1961, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 35)
    - Grace-New Haven Hospital Medical Board, 1955 (Box 54, Folder 36)
    - Joint Commission on Accreditation of Hospitals, 1957 (Box 54, Folder 37)
    - Medical Administrators Conference, 1939-1973, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 38)
    - New York Hospital meeting, 1943 (Box 54, Folder 39)
    - Society of Medical Administrators, 1950-1988 (Box 54, Folder 40-41)
    - Stanford University students, 1930s (Box 54, Folder 42)
    - United States Army War College, National Security Seminar, 1985 (Box 54, Folder 43)
    - UHEC, 1937, 1943 (Box 54, Folder 44)
    - Yale University
      - School of Nursing deans
        See: Oversize, folder 5
      - School of Public Health
        - Faculty, students, and staff, 1948-1965, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 45)
        - Hospital Administration Program, 1949-1968 (Box 54, Folder 46-47)
  - Individuals, ca. 1940s-1980s
    - A-I (Box 54, Folder 48)
    - K-Y (Box 54, Folder 49)
    - Unidentified (Box 54, Folder 50)
- Oversize
  - General files
    - MacLean, Basil, 1962 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Personal and Family Papers